-[eerie whooshing]
-[flames roaring]
[glitchy audio squawks]
[shaky breathing]
[low, mysterious voices whispering]
[child singing
eerily jaunty German folk song]
[song trails off]
[Eyk in German] Nina.
[foreboding music swells]
[flames crackle]
No.
Nina!
Nina.
No!
[glitchy audio squawks]
-[Maura in English] Wake up.
-[gasp echoes]
[knocking at door]
[drawer clatters]
[knocking continues]
[in German] We received this
from the company a couple minutes ago.
[disturbing music playing]
[in English] "Sink ship"?
[in German]
We tried to establish contact. No reply.
Captain.
There's more.
[disturbing music continues]
[sailor] I've never seen anything like it.
I have no idea why, but every compass
on board is doing the same thing.
What happened on the Prometheus?
[sailor pants]
Why is that boy the only one you found?
-[brooding cover of "White Rabbit" plays]
-♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ When logic and proportion ♪
♪ Have fallen sloppy dead ♪
♪ And the White Knight is
Talking backwards ♪
♪ And the Red Queen's off with her head ♪
[singer vocalizing]
[song trails off]
[uneasy music playing]
[high-pitched, mysterious tones playing]
[eerie, quizzical music plays]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[laborers chattering indistinctly]
[in English] The whole ship was empty?
You didn't find anyone on board?
Nobody except that boy?
Reckon they're dead?
What can kill more than 1,000 people?
What normally kills people. Other people.
Or maybe wolves.
Fucking wolves?
Do you know how many wolves
it would take to kill that many people?
Maybe one giant wolf?
[man 1] How many giant wolves
you seen in your life?
Why did it keep him alive,
that giant wolf of yours?
Why didn't it kill the boy?
-[man 2] Maybe it's him.
-Who?
The boy.
Maybe he's the wolf.
Maybe he's the wolf?
I don't even know where to begin.
He's the only survivor.
What other explanation could…
[in German] You, Olek!
Captain.
Find out how much coal
we have in the bunkers.
Don't tell anyone
what I just asked you to do.
[shrill grating]
[metal groaning, creaking]
[in English] I was looking for you.
[footsteps in distance]
[door opening, closing]
The boy, did he speak?
No.
Why did someone lock him in?
We searched the ship. There was no one.
But who sent the signal?
And who locked him in?
I don't know.
On the Prometheus, was there anything…?
Did you experience anything strange?
What do you mean by strange?
[child singing
eerily jaunty German folk song]
Do you hear that?
Hear what?
[singing continues]
[song trails off]
Are you all right?
[deep, foreboding chords play]
[Eyk breathes shakily]
[Anker in Danish] Don't be afraid of
what happened on that ship.
Our Lord will protect us.
Let us all pray.
Be with us, Lord, in a world
where the powers of darkness are strong.
Don't let the waves of darkness
close around us.
Have mercy on us
when we lack endurance and fortitude.
Strengthen us
when we are trapped by worry and fear.
O Holy Spirit,
may we be protected from evil
and all the falseness of the world.
Let your spirit light up before us
and testify with our spirit
that we are yours.
Then even darkness
will become light for us.
When you are together with us,
nothing shall harm us,
our Lord.
[door opens]
[man in English]
I'm, um… I'm really sorry.
Is this your cabin?
I didn't mean to intrude,
but I could hear noises inside.
It sounded like someone was whimpering.
Daniel.
Daniel Solace.
I'm your…
neighbor.
Maura Franklin.
Have we met before?
You look somehow familiar.
I don't think so.
[heavy, foreboding music plays]
[door closes]
I've brought you some food.
Don't you want to tell me what happened?
Who locked you in that cabinet?
Where are all the passengers?
Please, talk to me.
[mysterious music playing]
[high-pitched, mysterious tones playing]
[low, ominous chord quavers]
What is this?
[girl in Danish] It’s odd they only found
that boy, alone on the ship.
He must be really lonely.
I feel sad for him.
Don't you?
[girl sighs]
What is he going to do
once we get to America?
Is he going to live on his own?
Go to school there?
I've given this a lot of thought.
When we get to America, I will convince
Mother and Father to let me finish school.
They'll never let you.
We'll have to help build the church.
Way I see it, God gives us a calling.
Like He did with Mother and Father.
I think God wants me to become a doctor,
and I need to finish school for that.
Do you know what your calling is?
Go and bother Tove.
Or play with your doll
or do whatever else you usually do.
When did you stop being any fun?
[footsteps receding]
[water sloshes]
[footsteps approach]
[Ángel in Spanish]
You're a difficult man to find.
[uneasy synth music playing]
[uneasy music continues]
[Ángel] I want you to keep it.
For you.
[footsteps approaching]
[Tove in Danish] Krester?
[Ángel in Spanish] Krester?
So that's your name.
I'll see you around, Krester.
[in Danish] Who was that?
Huh? Who was that?
-What did he want?
-I don't know.
I don't know.
Remember, you promised me something.
[Eyk in German] When the ships were sold
a couple of months ago,
did anything about that
strike you as strange?
I…
I was just relieved
that they kept half of the crew.
That's not a given.
Selling the ships to an English company
and keeping half the German--
We're carrying barely any freight.
Just like the Prometheus.
Our cabins aren't fully occupied either.
The company travels this route
without making any profit.
45,000 tons of steel, fully seaworthy.
And only two words.
[in English] "Sink ship."
[foreboding music plays]
[crew murmuring]
[in German] Captain.
Everyone is waiting for your orders.
The crew, the passengers,
they're all asking questions.
They want to know what's wrong
with the boy and why we're not moving.
What am I supposed to tell them?
[tense synth music plays]
[Lucien in French] Spooky, isn't it?
[Lucien] What do you think
happened over there?
I've seen photographs of Japan.
It looks fascinating.
Astonishing flowers and trees.
The shape of houses.
Living behind rice paper walls.
I hope to one day
have the opportunity to see Japan.
[footsteps approaching]
[woman in Cantonese] Ling Yi.
What are you doing?
Come.
[Mrs. Wilson in French]
She's an exotic little bird.
You speak French?
A little.
Do you mind?
I couldn't help but notice
that your honeymoon doesn't seem
ideal.
I don't see how that's your business.
Why do you look at me like that?
I'm trying to figure out
what kind of man you are.
Oh, really?
What does that mean?
I was just wondering
if you're the kind of man
who might be interested
in a certain sort of…
distraction.
[tense, mysterious music plays]
[chuckles]
[Mrs. Wilson sighs]
Even if I was desperate,
I'd never be that desperate.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm not talking about myself.
I'm talking about that exotic little bird.
[tense percussive music playing]
[sailor in German]
Why would they want us to sink the ship?
And how would we even do that?
We do nothing.
We wait.
And the captain?
[Franz] They should have
replaced him back then.
You don't recover
from something like that.
Your own wife setting herself
and the three children on fire.
It haunts you forever.
[footsteps]
[child singing
eerily jaunty German folk song]
[song trails off]
Nina?
[low, mysterious voices whispering]
[door creaking]
[eerily jaunty German folk song resumes]
Nina?
[glitchy audio squawks]
[breathing heavily]
[flames whoosh]
[singing folk song]
♪ And should I be locked ♪
♪ Into the darkest dungeon ♪
♪ 'Tis all futile work ♪
♪ For my thoughts tear all gates ♪
♪ And walls asunder ♪
♪ Thoughts are free ♪
[woman] You're late.
The girls have been waiting for you.
[claps] Off you go. Get ready for bed.
[footsteps receding]
I'll warm up your dinner.
[breath quavering]
Nina.
The dreams are back.
But don't worry.
I'm sure she will be better soon.
[uneasy music plays]
You're not real.
Why would you say something like that?
[whimpering]
You should speak to Mama.
She doesn't like it when you're gone.
That's when the shadows come out.
I told her you cannot shackle
someone who prefers being at sea.
You have to let them go.
And if you're lucky, he'll wash back
into your arms with the next tide.
[quivering sob]
[uneasy music swells emotionally]
I miss you all so much.
[flames rushing]
No! No!
[grunts]
[coughing]
Nina.
[high-pitched, mysterious tones playing]
[Eyk breathing heavily]
[Eyk grunting]
[Eyk grunts with effort]
[panting]
[mysterious music playing]
[tense vibrato pitch]
[in English] When I was little…
about your age…
I got lost.
My father and I had gone bird hunting,
and from one moment to the next,
he was suddenly…
He was gone.
I spent the whole night there
until my father returned the next day.
That's when I found out I wasn't lost.
He'd left me there.
He watched me the whole night
as he had done
with my older brother before,
and he said that being alone like that
shows you what kind of a person you are.
I wasn't mad at him because he lied to me
or because he left me there.
I was mad at him
because he took away that one moment
where I thought
that I wasn't being watched.
What is th--
[frantic pounding at door]
[door opens]
-[Maura] Eyk.
-[Eyk] Where is the boy?
-[boy yelps]
-What happened on the Prometheus?
What's wrong with that ship? Tell me!
-[Maura] Stop it!
-I need to know!
Get off him! Get out!
[door slams shut]
[Maura] The hell is wrong with you?
[Eyk] There is something wrong
with that ship.
The destroyed telegraph, the compass.
He must know something.
Maybe I'm losing my mind,
but I heard something.
[clock ticking]
I heard my daughter's voice.
She's dead, and I heard her voice.
I didn't only hear her, I saw her!
I think you need to calm down.
You're not thinking straight.
[ticking continues]
[ticking stops]
I'm sorry.
[Daniel] Maura.
It's an Irish name, isn't it?
But you're not Irish.
[door opens]
No, I'm not.
[high-pitched, mysterious tones playing]
[lock clicks]
[mysterious music swells, fades away]
[Jérôme in French] Spooky, isn't it?
I didn't mean to startle you.
Are you part of the crew?
You don't look like crew.
People say we shouldn't
judge anyone by their looks.
It's impossible though, isn't it?
I'm sure you made your mind up
about me as soon as you saw me.
It must be hard working on a ship.
It's a bit like a prison, isn't it?
Even the birds up there
have their own prison.
They can't escape who they are.
And neither can we.
[tense, mysterious music playing]
Do I know you from somewhere?
My name is Clémence.
Jérôme.
I have to go.
You're right.
I did make up my mind about you
the moment I saw you.
[stressful music plays]
[sailor in German] There he is.
Hey, you!
[tense percussive beats play]
[Franz] Stop!
Stop him!
[grunts]
I knew you were a liar from the get-go.
Someone stole a crew uniform yesterday.
You wouldn't happen to know
who that someone is?
Do you know what we do with stowaways?
[intense drumbeat plays]
[drumbeat tempo increases]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[passengers chattering]
Krester, Mother is still looking for Ada.
No one has seen her for hours.
She wants us to help find her.
Where did you get that?
Give it to me.
Was it that man who gave it to you?
You fool.
Why did you accept it?
Because.
Because it was nice of him
to give it to me.
And what did he want?
Rich people don't give you
anything for free.
They always want something in return.
You of all people should know that.
[low, ominous chord plays]
[in Spanish] You look like
you got some rest.
[Ramiro] I suppose
it wasn't a dream after all.
Why are we still here?
-Do you think they'll send someone?
-Send who?
The police.
There are hundreds of people
missing from that boat.
The last thing
they're interested in is us.
That boy.
The look in his eyes.
It was terrifying.
[Tove in Danish] Let go of me.
Hey!
You rich fuckers think
everything belongs to you.
That you can take whatever you want.
Keep your dirty hands off my brother.
If you touch him again,
I'll fucking cut your dick off.
[in Spanish] What?
Don't look at me like that.
Don't judge me.
Don't you dare judge me.
I've never pretended
to be someone I'm not.
[bell ringing in distance]
[breathing shakily]
[knocking at door]
[knocking continues]
[in German] I…
I found out what you wanted to know.
And?
The bunkers are half-loaded.
Two of them are almost empty.
So roughly 3,000 tons remaining.
Captain, when will we get back on course?
Captain.
[door closes]
[lock clicks]
[in Polish] Fuck.
[eerie, mysterious music plays]
[in English] I don't even know
if you understand what I'm saying.
But if you do, I'm looking for someone.
My brother.
He's been missing for four months.
I think that he was on the Prometheus.
But I know that he's not dead
because I think he sent me this.
This looks exactly like the sign
on your neck.
Why do you have that?
What happened on the Prometheus?
[bell ringing in distance]
[porter] The captain will hopefully answer
your questions.
Just, everyone, please assemble
in the dining room.
What's happening?
They're not telling us.
That's what you get when you have
a bloody German running this shit show.
Everyone, please assemble
in the dining room.
The captain would like
to address the situation.
Try to get some sleep.
I'll be back soon. I promise.
[tense music plays]
[door closes]
[lock clicks]
[porter ringing bell]
Everyone, please assemble
in the dining room.
The captain would like
to address the current situation.
Everyone, please assemble
in the dining room.
The captain would like…
[in Spanish] Why do you always
have to spoil the mood?
That's what concerns you?
That I'm spoiling the mood?
-What are you so afraid of?
-I'm afraid they will find out.
Find out what?
That you're not really a priest
or not really my brother?
Everyone probably
already knows the latter.
Do you really think anyone out there
believes we're brothers?
Look at yourself.
You are pathetic.
For Christ's sake,
you're not even Spanish.
You're not my brother.
You're not a priest.
You're Ramiro.
A goddamn Portuguese servant.
But it doesn't matter.
People are so occupied
with their own bullshit
that they don't give a damn.
Everything's a game to you.
For God's sake, Ramiro.
[Ramiro] It is, isn't it?
All of it.
Your mother was right.
You use people.
You don't care.
Not about me, not about anyone!
[restrained seething]
[moody synth music playing]
[chuckles wryly]
You're just jealous.
That's all.
[music intensifies]
[both moaning]
[bed creaks]
[tense chords play]
[ragged breathing]
[music trails off]
[lock clicks]
[ominous, plaintive music plays]
[ominous music builds]
[floorboards creak]
[in English] I'm so sorry.
[wind rushing]
[music trails off]
[crowd murmurs anxiously]
[crowd quiets down]
I've decided to turn the ship around
and tow the Prometheus back to Europe.
[overlapping agitated chatter]
The Kerberos doesn't hold enough coal
to tow the Prometheus to our destination.
The miles behind are
less than the miles ahead,
which is why we're turning back.
[in French] This is ridiculous!
We can't turn around. Out of the question!
What's the point in saving an empty ship?
It doesn't make any sense.
[in English] How many people
are on the Kerberos?
1,612, passengers and crew.
Well, I'd say 1,611 of those are against
your decision to turn the ship around.
[crowd murmurs angrily]
[Mrs. Wilson] Maybe you're the captain,
but you cannot make choices
against everyone else's interests.
[passenger] She's right!
I've made my decision.
[agitated chatter intensifies]
This is insane.
You're not going to change my mind.
There is something wrong with that ship.
And the ship company's trying to hide it.
"Sink ship"?
And that's not everything.
I think someone wanted me
to find that ship.
I got this letter in a package,
along with a picture of my family.
[mysterious music plays]
Who sent this?
What does the Prometheus
have to do with my family?
Have you ever lost someone?
It's like you're dying with them.
[mysterious music intensifies]
They can move on.
You're stuck.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe this is insane.
Maybe I'm insane.
But I need to find out
what happened on that ship.
You don't understand.
We can't go back, and I can't go back.
[tense, staticky music builds]
[Eyk] I'm sorry.
But I'm turning the ship around.
I think he's wrong.
I don't think he understands
the consequences of his decision.
A ship with this many passengers?
They're not going to sit still
and just let it happen.
You don't look keen to go back either.
[passengers chattering]
You must have family back home?
I don't.
[Franz in German] He's acting against
a clear order from the company.
And we will all bear the consequences.
Why does he want
to tow the Prometheus back?
[Franz] Perhaps we should just do it.
[sailor] Do what?
Sink the ship.
[ship creaking in distance]
Perhaps.
[suspenseful music builds]
[unsettling choral vocalizations]
[music trails off]
[knocking at door]
[door opens]
[Franz] Captain.
I think you'd better come with me.
["Child in Time" by Deep Purple plays]
♪ Sweet child in time ♪
-[telegraph ticking]
-♪ You'll see the line ♪
♪ The line that's drawn between ♪
♪ Good and bad ♪
♪ See the blind man ♪
♪ Shooting at the world ♪
♪ Bullets flying ♪
♪ Oh, taking toll ♪
♪ If you've been bad ♪
♪ Oh, Lord, I bet you have ♪
♪ And you've not been hit ♪
♪ Oh, by flying lead ♪
♪ You'd better close your eyes ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ Bow your head ♪
♪ Wait for the ricochet ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ I wanna hear you singing ♪
[singer continues vocalizing]
[song ends]
[moody, mysterious outro music plays]