-[gunshot]
-[horse whinnying]
[swords clanging]
-[blade slicing flesh]
-[man screams]
[unsettling music swells]
[both grunting]
[Jérôme panting heavily]
[in French] That's not right.
We shouldn't be doing this.
He's been dead two days.
I don't think he'll mind.
What if they find us? Know what they do
to soldiers who desert the Legion?
We haven't got messages for weeks.
They probably don't know
we're still alive.
With this fucking idiot dead,
there's no one to give me commands.
The supply troops
should've been here days ago.
I'm not going to starve here
and end up like this idiot.
Jérôme.
This will work.
I promise.
[soldiers clamoring]
It's a seven-day walk
to the next military post.
I'm a wounded lieutenant,
and you're the hero who saved me.
And that's it.
Hey. They will send us back home.
It's either that or die out here.
Come back to reality, my friend.
Help me.
-Stop!
-What?
The supply troops
will be here any day now.
We shouldn't be doing this.
[tense percussive music plays]
You're right.
I'm sorry.
What was I thinking, my friend?
What was I thinking?
[glitchy audio squawks]
[Maura in English] Wake up.
[Olek in Polish] Are you all right?
Easy.
[in Portuguese] Calm down.
Everything is all right.
[door clanking heavily]
[in German] Franz, that is mutiny.
You can't do that.
[mutineers clamoring]
Get up.
Let's go.
[clamoring continues]
You too.
Franz!
What is this? What are you planning?
Let me out of here!
Franz!
[door slams shut]
[low, menacing music plays]
[Franz] Throw them overboard!
Who knows what they died of.
[thunder booms faintly]
Olek! I said throw them overboard.
Come on!
[menacing, oppressive music plays]
Same for you too.
[distorted, warped tones play]
-[brooding cover of "White Rabbit" plays]
-♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ When logic and proportion ♪
♪ Have fallen sloppy dead ♪
♪ And the White Knight is
Talking backwards ♪
♪ And the Red Queen's off with her head ♪
[singer vocalizing]
[song trails off]
[tense, agitating music plays]
[passengers, mutineers clamoring]
[in English] Stay in your cabin!
[in Norwegian] I'll go to the right!
[in Portuguese] Clear the corridors.
[in Russian] Keep walking.
Do as I say! Come on.
[in German] Please.
[in Portuguese] Get in!
[in French] Leave me alone.
[in Portuguese] Let go of me!
[muffled clamoring, shouting]
[muffled bang, shouting]
[in English] They will not hurt you.
They want to turn the ship back around.
Don't worry.
[door opens]
[in Portuguese] Keep going.
Go. Go. Go. Go.
[door slams, lock clicks]
[in English] Stay here.
[door closes]
[tense music continues]
[in German] Did you find her?
We searched the whole horizon.
No sign of the Prometheus.
[Franz] That's impossible.
She was tied to us.
[crew member] Maybe she didn't disappear.
Maybe it's us who disappeared.
The compasses are working again.
At our last location,
our bow was facing east.
Now we're facing west.
What does that mean?
Maybe we're not
where we're supposed to be.
I have no idea why, but somehow
we're back in the position we were
when we deviated
from our course three days ago.
Wherever we are,
our destination lies west.
Turn the engine back on.
Full power.
[crew members murmur]
[bell rings]
[man in Norwegian]
There are new rules on this ship now.
And we want answers.
Why are people dying here?
Tell us right now.
You didn't care about our lives before,
and we don't care about yours now.
This ship will go to America.
With or without your help.
[rifles cocking]
[in German] Wait.
There is something you need to know.
The morning we returned
from the Prometheus,
we received a message from…
from the ship company.
[in Danish] Two days ago,
they got a message from the ship company.
[in German] It read, "Sink ship."
[in Danish] It said
we should sink the ship we found.
[man in German] I think the ship company
wanted us to sink that ship
so no one would get off it alive.
That boy they brought back.
Since he's been on board,
people have started dying.
That's not a coincidence.
[Iben in Danish] What did he say?
Tove, what did he say?
-The boy they brought back--
-Krester.
He thinks he is causing all the deaths.
[exhales softly]
[passengers murmur]
The devil dresses as an angel.
Do you believe me now?
The devil is not going to get his way.
Find the boy.
[crowd clamoring]
[Tove] Krester.
[mutineers chattering faintly]
[man in French] You!
[in Portuguese] Let's go!
[forceful banging]
[Eyk grunting]
[Ramiro grunts]
[loud thud]
[in Portuguese] What was that?
[gunshot]
[in Polish] Think there's
something wrong with them?
Maybe this happened
to the passengers on the Prometheus.
[thunder rumbles]
[Olek] And they all died like that.
[ragged breathing]
[body splashes]
No. Best to keep your head down.
Do you understand?
[suspenseful music playing]
[glitchy audio burst]
[gasps]
[panicked panting]
Are you all right?
Hey, easy.
Easy.
[unsettling music playing]
[Clémence in French] Tell me the truth.
Where were you last night?
What is that?
As if you cared.
I'm your wife.
And how is that working out for you?
What is wrong with you?
There is a mutiny out there,
and the only thing you're interested in
is finding more ways to hurt me.
Life hurts.
The moment you think you've got it all,
it smacks you in the face.
Want to know what this is?
It's potassium bromide.
It's supposed to help with the seizures.
What seizures?
There is something inside my head.
If I don't take it, I wriggle
on the floor like a fucking lunatic.
And if I take it, I can't get a hard-on.
The truth is, I will die.
I don't have much time left.
Might be only a few days or weeks.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because, frankly, you don't give a fuck
if I'm dead or alive.
[uneasy, menacing notes play]
How did this get here?
-How did this get here?
-I put it there. I thought it was yours.
Where did you find it?
You're hurting me!
[Clémence grunts]
[tense percussive music plays]
I'm sorry.
[panting]
[Maura in English] Get off me!
[in German] We found her
on her way to the captain's quarters.
[in English]
I need to speak to the captain.
[in German] He's not the captain anymore.
And passengers are supposed to stay
in their cabins.
Take her back. Lock her in.
[in English] You have no idea
what is going on here.
You're making a huge mistake.
I need to see the captain.
[foreboding music drones]
He's not the man you think he is.
No. You're not the man you think you are.
You're just a little boy,
toying with power.
[harsh, menacing synth music plays]
[clamoring in distance]
[Portuguese] I don't know
if this is a good idea.
[Anker in Danish]
I tried to hear His voice.
God's voice.
To guide us through this.
But He doesn't talk to me
like He talks to your mother.
You truly believe Mother?
That the boy is evil.
What if she's right?
What if it's all true?
Maybe God gave you a gift.
Maybe you do carry the light
inside of you.
He told her…
that the devil…
will try to take everything away from us.
We cannot let that happen.
[mutineers chattering]
[in German] This is it.
[in Danish] Open it.
[chatter subsides]
[grunting]
No. Step aside!
[in German] Hold on!
I'm on your side.
We're all on the same side.
We just want the boy.
[in English] What did he say?
What did you just say?
You want the boy?
He's not sick, if that's what you think.
He's been in my room since we got back.
He hasn't been in contact with anyone.
It's not his fault that people are dying.
[in Danish] Search her.
Krester, search her.
[harsh, menacing synth music plays]
Here's the key.
Open the door.
[lock clicks]
[Iben] Where's the boy?
Where's the boy?
Mum.
Mum, the boy isn't here.
Okay?
Search every cabin and lock the doors.
No one goes in or out.
Find the boy.
Where is he?
[Iben] Lock her in.
[lock clicks]
[in English] No!
[agitated breathing]
[knocking]
What's going on up there?
Why is no one telling us anything?
No one ever tells us anything.
What is that for?
Protection.
Protection from what?
The wolves.
The…
It's vampires that don't like garlic.
Maybe werewolves don't like it either.
They seem kind of the same.
They're not the same. Vampires can fly.
I'm pretty sure werewolves can't fly.
How do you know? You've never seen one.
Of course I haven't. They don't exist.
No. I've never seen Russia.
-Right.
-But I'm pretty sure that exists.
[worker 1] That's completely different.
You've seen it on a map.
[worker 2] A map's a drawing.
By that logic,
I've seen drawings of werewolves.
So they exist then.
Do you want me to see
if I can get you one of these?
[worker 1] No.
[enigmatic music playing]
[high-pitched, mysterious tones play]
[door clanks]
[machinery humming]
[electronic trilling]
[power surging]
[electricity sparking]
[body splashes]
[in Polish] No. Jérôme, no.
Don't get us in trouble.
[resigned sigh]
[in German] Hey!
He's gone!
He jumped.
[crew members clamor]
[man in German] Where is he?
There's nothing here.
[in French] Try to the left!
-[in German] Stop!
-No!
[bullet ricochets]
[crew members clamoring]
[unsettling percussive music plays]
[glitchy audio burst]
[crew member 1 in German] Where is he?
[crew member 2] He went this way.
[crew member 1] Find him.
Where is the vermin?
[lock clicks]
[footsteps passing by rapidly]
[muffled chatter]
[in French] What happened to you?
I shouldn't have come here.
You can stay.
I mean, until whoever
is looking for you is gone.
I don't think that's a good idea.
Where are you going?
I've seen it before.
People taking power who don't deserve it.
It never ends well.
I'm going to free the captain.
Jérôme.
I will help you.
[Franz in German]
The Black man. Where did he go?
Did you help him?
Huh?
No.
If you're lying…
It's all right. He's on our side.
[captive in German]
You have no idea what you've done.
We're sitting on a powder keg
that's about to explode.
There are over 1,500 souls on board.
From God knows
how many different countries.
And you just armed them all.
We have five days before we reach land.
Until then, we give them what they want.
And what's that?
An explanation for why people are dying.
The boy.
Check all cabins!
[in Norwegian] Hey, you.
[grunts]
[in Danish] Look over here!
Where are they?
[in German] He's not here.
[woman in English] Over here!
[man] Where is the boy?
[agitated clamoring]
[in German] Open the door!
You're hurting me.
Come out.
Open the door!
Come.
-Open up!
-Over here.
[man in English] Where is the boy?
[pounding at door]
[in Spanish] Hey. What's going on here?
What are you looking for?
Hey, no. Put that down.
Krester, tell him to put it back.
[in Danish] Why does he know your name?
Krester?
[unsettling music plays]
I wish He would have taken you
instead of Ada.
Let's move on.
[in Spanish] Krester.
[menacing chords swell]
[in English] These shafts,
they were also on the Prometheus.
What are they for?
Why don't you tell me
what's going on here?
Stay here. I need to find the captain.
[high-pitched, mysterious tones play]
[audio warbles disconcertingly]
[doorknob rattles]
How… How did you do that?
Where are we going?
[tense percussive music plays]
[in German] Find the captain.
[mutineers clamoring in distance]
[in French] We're on your side.
-[clang]
-[Eyk grunts]
[loud clang]
[in English] We're trying
to get to one of the lifeboats,
get off the Kerberos.
Maybe I can fix the telegraph
on the Prometheus and call for help.
[in French] They want to get a lifeboat.
Leave the ship
and take refuge on the Prometheus.
-I will help you.
-Me too.
[in English] This way.
[mutineers grow louder]
[splash]
[loud clang in distance]
[passenger whimpering desperately]
[jarring stinger]
[in French] Clémence?
[high-pitched, mysterious tone plays]
[man in Norwegian]
The boy isn't here either.
[man in Swedish] Look here.
[audio warbles disconcertingly]
[man in German]
Lock him in with the others.
[high-pitched, mysterious tones play]
[dark, disturbing synth music plays]
[door closes]
[in English] Eyk.
I've been looking for you.
Are you all right?
[Eyk] What's going on here?
What do you know about the Prometheus?
And stop lying.
[menacing music builds]
-[in German] Franz!
-Get out of the way.
I said, get out of the way!
Hey!
Don't even think about it.
[in Danish] Listen.
We just want the boy.
Nothing else.
[in English] Boy.
[Maura] No.
No. No, no, no. What are you doing?
[in French] This isn't right.
[in German] Stop!
[in French] No! Jérôme! No!
[mutineers shout, murmur]
No! No! Jérôme, no!
[man in English] Take the boy!
[in French] No! Jérôme, no! No, no, no!
No! Jérôme!
-[glitchy audio squawks]
-[gasping]
[in French] Lucien?
What am I doing here?
Where am I?
[chain rattles]
I must have hit you harder than I thought.
What is happening?
Get me out of here! Get me out of here!
I can't do that.
I can be someone else now.
I'll return to France a different man.
As a lieutenant.
You betrayed me.
We were friends.
Once I reach the post,
I'll tell them where to find you.
I'll tell them you're a deserter.
Who do you think they will believe?
Here, take this.
Take it.
You can trade it in prison.
This isn't real.
Why is this happening again?
I'm sorry, my friend.
I really am.
[grunts, struggles]
[straining]
-[glitchy audio squawks]
-[gasps]
[panting for breath]
[flinches]
[shuddering gasp]
[low, foreboding music plays]
[in Danish] What are you doing?
Krester, have you gone mad as well?
You can't honestly believe her.
You're willing to sacrifice that boy
for Mother's love?
You know what?
You have to stop blaming us
for what happened to you.
Not everything is about you.
Ada is dead.
More people are dying.
And you're only interested in
your own misery.
Don't do this. Don't take their side.
[suspenseful music playing]
[muffled thud]
[muffled struggling]
[in French] You're alive.
You have no idea what I've been through
to get on this ship.
I'm not planning to die here.
They are out of control.
And it's up to us to stop them.
[Iben in Danish]
Don't be fooled by his appearance.
The devil comes in many disguises.
He is taking what is ours.
Collecting our souls,
just as he did on that other ship.
[crowd murmuring]
But we know pain and sacrifice!
It will not break us!
[crowd calling out in assent]
Throw the boy overboard!
[gunshot echoes]
[clamoring subsides]
[in English] Stop!
Don't do this, please!
He's not the reason people are dying.
[in Danish] We can't let them stop us!
[gunshot]
[all shouting, struggling]
[sounds of combat grow muffled]
[low, foreboding music plays]
[no audible dialogue]
[resounding splash]
[mournful dirge plays]
[in English, muffled] Maura! Maura!
[in normal volume] Maura!
[sounds of conflict, struggle resume]
We have to get out of here!
[in German] Retreat!
Fall back!
[Lucien in French] Jérôme!
Let her go!
How did you get here?
How did you find me?
Leave her alone!
[Eyk in German] Fall back!
[in French] Why were you with him?
What did he tell you?
-Don't believe a word he says.
-You know him?
[in English] Let's hide at the bar!
[indistinct chatter]
[in Polish] You were lucky.
[Maura in English]
I can't believe they killed the boy.
He didn't even fight it.
It's like he accepted it was coming.
[tense music plays]
[footsteps approaching]
[Eyk] I need to talk to you. Now.
I think it's time to tell me the truth.
I found the logbook. This was in it.
It's the passenger list of the Prometheus.
Here. That's your name.
[intense, mysterious synth music plays]
This is impossible.
Who are you really?
[loud clattering]
[mysterious rumbling]
[energy thrumming]
[thrumming stops abruptly]
[all murmur in shock]
["(Don’t Fear) The Reaper"
by Blue Öyster Cult plays]
♪ All our times have come ♪
♪ Here but now they're gone ♪
♪ Seasons don't fear the reaper ♪
♪ Nor do the wind, the sun or the rain ♪
♪ We can be like they are ♪
♪ Come on, baby, don't fear the reaper ♪
♪ Baby, take my hand ♪
♪ Don't fear the reaper ♪
♪ We'll be able to fly ♪
♪ Baby, I'm your man ♪
[singer vocalizing]
[song trails off]
[moody, mysterious outro music plays]