[unsettling drumbeat]
[wind rushing]
[woman] The brain is wider than the sky
For put them side by side
The one the other will contain
With ease, and you beside
The brain is deeper than the sea
[jarring stinger]
For hold them, blue to blue
The one the other will absorb
As sponges buckets do
[water rushing]
[unsettling music swells]
[panting]
Father? [continues panting]
I… I know what I have seen. I'm not crazy!
What did you do to my brother?
Where is my brother?
He was on the Prometheus.
He found out
what you were doing on these ships.
Why don't I remember?
What have you done to my memory?
[struggling] I'm not crazy!
Wake up.
[staticky distortion]
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
"Steamship lost at sea."
"Prometheus still missing
after four months."
[eerie, unsettling music plays]
"I found out what our father did.
Meet me in New York."
"Don't trust anyone."
"Your brother."
[jagged drumbeat]
[haunting vocalizations]
I am Maura Franklin.
Born in Morefield.
Today is October 19th,
1899.
I am not crazy.
I am Maura Franklin.
[haunting vocalizations intensify]
[vocalizations trail off]
[indistinct chatter]
[sharp, high-pitched note ringing]
[note intensifies]
[low, menacing chords playing]
-[brooding cover of "White Rabbit" plays]
-♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ When logic and proportion ♪
♪ Have fallen sloppy dead ♪
♪ And the White Knight is
Talking backwards ♪
♪ And the Red Queen's off with her head ♪
[singer vocalizing]
[song trails off]
[ship's horn blares]
[shovel scraping coal]
[worker yelling indistinctly]
-[whistle blowing]
-[leadman] All right, now!
[worker] Moving on! Moving on!
Yeah, I'm not superstitious.
All I'm saying is
it's been four months now,
and they still haven't found
the Prometheus.
A big ship, just… just disappearing.
-It's odd.
-It didn't disappear, it sank.
End of story.
You don't know that.
[worker 2] Whose turn is it?
-[worker 3] Stop!
-[worker 2] We're not getting any coal.
Oh, fuck me, not again.
[machinery clanks]
Oi, Polack!
Climb up. Fix it.
[bell ringing]
[man 1] Last year, at the docks,
there was this man. Told me about…
[workers chatter indistinctly]
[whistle blows]
[conversations continue indistinctly]
[coal pile clattering]
[tense, unnerving music playing]
[loud clanging]
[man 2] Polack! Move the bloody lever.
[machinery clang echoes]
[indistinct, genteel conversation]
[in French] I can't stop thinking about
that ship that disappeared.
Do you think it sank?
That's the only explanation.
Otherwise they'd have found it.
It makes me uneasy to travel
on a ship from the same company.
But what are the chances of two ships
from the same company
sinking one after the other?
Don't you think?
Are you listening to me, Lucien?
[in Cantonese]
Why would one need so many knives?
[woman 1] I don't know.
Just pretend you know what you are doing.
[woman 1] Hurry up and eat.
Just play along.
[in French] Lucien?
Whatever you say.
[hushed, indistinct whispering]
[hushed whispering continuing]
[genteel conversation continuing]
[man 1 in Spanish] Waiter.
More.
Don't you think you've had enough?
The problem is that you're a fucking bore.
Ángel, lower your voice.
"Ángel, lower your voice.
Ángel, calm down."
None of these poor bastards
understands a word I'm saying.
Why should I?
[footsteps approaching]
[woman 2 in English] Miss Franklin.
What a rare treat
to see you up here so early. May I?
[chair scraping]
Don't make such a face.
I'm doing you a favor.
I mean, I get it.
I've traveled by myself for years now.
I know sometimes it's preferable
to seek solitude over company,
but I also know how fast one is judged,
and there are already rumors circulating.
Is it true that you're a doctor?
My focus was… is on the human brain.
They let you cut up brains?
Women in England are allowed
to study, not practice.
That's what they do, don't they?
They show you the world,
and then they tell you you can't have it.
See that man over there?
Dr. Reginald Murray.
He's dumb as a stump.
His father was a doctor,
and so was his father,
and so on and so on.
Born a boy and spoiled silly.
[man] Perhaps we could've
all gone outside on the deck.
Tell me.
What is so interesting about the brain?
The brain drives our thoughts,
our behavior.
It holds all of the secrets
of the universe.
The secrets of the universe?
There's a hidden world inside each of us
which only needs to be deciphered.
Aren't some things
better left in the dark?
I mean, look at them.
Why do you think they're all here?
Nervous wreck of a priest
and his horny-looking brother.
That exotic little bird over there
with her sheep of a servant.
And those French honeymooners
who clearly didn't marry
for the right reasons.
All running away from something.
Why else would someone want
to go somewhere different?
[unsettling, mysterious music plays]
[cups all clattering in unison]
[cups setting in unison]
And if I'm not mistaken,
that's also the case for you, my dear.
[door flings open]
[music stops]
[in Danish] Excuse me. Excuse me.
[door hinges squeaking]
Excuse me.
We need help.
Uh, we need a…
a doctor.
My… My sister…
A doctor? A doctor?
She needs… We don't know what to do.
We need a doctor.
[door slams open]
[dark, intense industrial music]
I'm begging you.
She's dying.
We don't know what to do. I'm begging.
[yelling] She's dying. I'm begging you.
I am begging you!
A doctor! We need a doctor!
Let go of me! Stop!
Help us!
A doctor! You're killing her!
We need a doctor!
[door creaks, slams shut]
[in English] I'm sure
you can do without my company.
[passengers murmur apprehensively]
[low, unsettling brass notes play]
[man 1 in Danish] We need a doctor.
We need a doctor! We need a doctor!
[man 2 in German] Shut up.
You don't belong up here, creep.
Next time, I'll throw you overboard.
Got it?
[grunts]
[gate creaks]
[chains rattling]
[in English] Ma'am.
[dark, intense industrial music playing]
[door lock clanking]
Stop!
You were looking for a doctor.
[in Danish] Are you a doctor?
Okay. Come.
This way.
[wailing in pain]
[grunts]
[crowd murmurs anxiously]
[woman 1 wails]
[woman 1 grunting]
[in English] How far along are you?
How far along is she?
How long have you been with child?
How many months?
How long? Seven months? Six?
[child in Danish] Seven.
[in English] Seven?
[in Danish] Get it out of me!
Get it out now!
She thinks the baby is dead.
[woman 2] Who is that, Krester?
Why did you bring her?
You idiot. We don't need help.
-[Maura in English] Give me that.
-[woman 1 wails]
[woman 2 in Danish] No. This is wrong.
We don't even know who or what she is.
You must do something.
-[woman 1 straining]
-[faint heartbeat]
[in English] I can hear its heartbeat.
The pain might come
from the umbilical cord.
It's rare,
but they can get tangled up in it.
I have to turn the baby.
[in Danish]
I think she wants to turn the baby.
[tense percussive music plays]
[in English] This might hurt.
[grunting]
[in Danish] No. No. This is wrong.
Do something.
She's going to kill it. It's God's child.
-Anker!
-What do you want me to do?
[woman 1 grunts, whimpers]
[agonized wail]
[tense percussive music continues]
[ragged breathing]
[shrieks]
[tense music trails away]
[panting heavily]
[woman 1 gasps]
[bystanders chattering]
[in English] She's fine.
[overlapping anxious chatter]
[in Danish] Thanks.
[bell ringing]
-[whistle blows in distance]
-[workers chattering indistinctly]
[coal clattering]
[enigmatic synth chords reverberate]
[indistinct conversation]
[synth chords drone]
[indistinct conversation continues]
[door hinges creak]
-[muffled grunting]
-[disturbing synth music plays]
[man grunts]
[bed squeaking]
[breathing heavily]
[man inhales sharply]
[music warbles dissonantly]
[clothing rustling]
[in French] Maybe if you helped,
instead of lying there, playing dead.
Are you telling me this is my fault?
Stop your little act. It's pretentious.
Your parents aren't around anymore.
It's fine.
You don't love me. You never did.
This is not a marriage.
It's an arrangement.
So you can stop pretending.
[door clanks open]
[cabin door closes]
[dissonant music continues]
[passengers chattering indistinctly]
[in Danish] Thanks a lot.
For helping my sister.
When I grow up,
I want to be a doctor just like you.
[in English] I'm so sorry.
I don't understand what you're saying.
[in Danish] Thanks.
Do you have children?
[jarring audio distortion]
[in English] No. I…
I, uh…
I can't have children.
[haunting vocalizations]
[Maura] Hmm?
[in Danish] Here.
This is all we have.
[vocalizations continue]
[Maura panting]
[staccato audio glitches]
[music crescendos]
-[panting]
-[music and vocalizations fade away]
[in German] Did you get lost?
[gasps]
[in English] I didn't see you there.
[liquid sloshes]
[wind rushing]
[wind whistles]
-[chains rattle]
-[gate clanks]
You're the captain.
What were you doing down there?
I don't really see
how that's any of your business.
Passengers from first class
aren't allowed down there.
There are rules on this ship,
and they shouldn't be challenged.
Who made those rules,
and to whose benefit
were they put in place?
[sailor in German] Captain!
Captain, you have to see this.
[ominous synth music quavers]
For 20 minutes,
we've been receiving the same signal.
I think it's from the lost ship.
The Prometheus.
[steady clicking, clacking]
[sailors chattering]
Forty-four. Fifty-seven.
Fifty-nine. Sixty.
[sailor 1] They're just sending
these coordinates.
Over and over. Nothing else.
We can't be sure it's the Prometheus.
How far away are we?
[sailor 2] We're right here.
At 18 knots.
[captain] This is odd.
If they drifted off course
four months ago,
the current should have taken them
north of their route, not south.
How did they end up here?
Approximately seven hours.
We're changing course.
New destination. 42.4 north.
44.57 west.
[sailor 2] Reduce speed to nine knots.
Prepare for turning.
Bring rudder angle to 20 degrees port.
New course, 230 degrees.
Twenty degrees port side. 230 degrees.
SLOW
[bell ringing]
[leadman in English]
Lads! Prepare for turning!
Increase power on starboard shafts.
Close all furnaces on port side!
Hurry up, will ya?
[in Polish] Why are we turning?
[workers clamoring]
Where are we going?
-[in English] Why turn ship?
-You just do what you're told.
Here, don't ask questions.
[whistle blowing]
[priest in Spanish] It's as though
you want everyone to find out, Ángel.
Can't you be a little more careful?
-More careful?
-I'm just saying…
Don't you think it would be better
to attract less attention?
Do you know what the big difference is
between you and I, dear brother?
I have no fear.
And you're consumed by it.
Why don't you have a little chat with God?
Ask him why he turned you into a sheep
and me into a wolf.
[chuckles]
[ship rumbling]
What's happening?
I don't know.
It's turning.
Don't be ridiculous. Why would it turn?
The goddamn ship is turning!
[ship's horn blaring]
Do you think we're going back?
No, this can't be happening.
We can't go back.
Dear Lord, please don't let us go back.
[suspenseful music plays]
I can't.
[ominous industrial synth music plays]
[horn blares]
[breathing shallowly]
[ship creaking, groaning]
[in Danish] Tove?
Tove. Tove, wake up.
Are you awake?
[gasps]
Where are the others?
They're all outside, looking for the ship.
What ship?
The one that got lost at sea.
-What are you talking about?
-They turned our ship around.
They got a signal
from the other ship that is lost.
[grunts] They turned our ship around?
Are we going back?
No, silly.
I already told you.
They're looking for that lost ship.
[ship groaning]
Remember the story of the ghost ship
that you told me once?
Where the passengers had all sinned
because they killed a whale.
And the spirits of the sea got so angry,
they sent a huge storm
towards the ship and caused black waves.
And when they woke up the next morning,
they had all turned into shadows.
Maybe that's what happened
to that other ship.
Imagine there's only shadows on board.
Stop that nonsense.
And don't let Mother and Father hear it.
You hear me?
[bed frame creaking]
[faint, rapid musical notes flitting]
[in English]
"What is lost, will be found."
[knocking at door]
May I step inside?
Passengers shouldn't be
in this part of the ship either.
Is it true that you found the Prometheus?
[door closes]
We received a signal.
Coordinates. It's not quite clear yet,
but they might come from the Prometheus.
You think the passengers,
they're still alive?
It's been four months. It's unlikely.
But if they rationed food,
they could've made it.
Or at least some of them.
Why do you take such an interest
in the Prometheus?
Did you know anyone on board?
I… [breathes shakily]
I just noticed we turned the ship.
I just want to know
when we're returning to our course.
I will address the current situation
in the dining room in an hour.
All your questions will be answered then.
[mysterious music playing]
[mysterious music intensifying]
[objects in drawer rattling]
[mysterious music continuing]
Mrs. Wilson.
I saw you talking together at breakfast.
I thought I made myself clear.
No talking.
Yes, madam.
[door opening]
[tense synth music plays]
And tell that one to cheer up a little.
[glass clinking]
[indistinct chatter]
[chatter subsides]
Six hours ago, we received a message.
Coordinates. Southwest of our course.
We believe this message
comes from the Prometheus,
the ship that went missing
a couple of months ago.
Believe?
[anxious murmuring]
You're not sure
the signal comes from lost ship?
[Eyk] We're not.
But the communication
technology we're using
on the ships of this company is rare.
It can reach further distances
than that on other ships.
The coordinates were
seven hours away from us.
And there's no other ship
from our company traveling this route.
-What else did the message say?
-Just that.
The location.
[Mrs. Wilson] And they didn't
identify themselves as the Prometheus?
Nor did they say
they were in need of any help?
So we changing course
because of message from unknown sender,
who did not ask for help.
[tense, rapid percussive music plays]
The Prometheus carried 1,423 passengers.
Some might still be alive.
After four months?
[crowd murmurs in agitation]
[Ángel in Spanish] Captain.
[in English]
My brother and I, and all these people,
we paid good money for this trip.
[crowd clamors]
Seven days to get to New York. No detours.
[clamoring continues]
[low synth chords blare]
[panting]
[woman in French] There you are.
What are you so worked up about?
What does it matter to you if we arrive
in New York a couple of days late?
[dissonant music warbles]
Lucien?
[unnerving synth music playing]
[dissonant music continues]
[in Polish] I'm sorry.
I am very sorry, sir.
I know I am not allowed in here.
I was just having a break.
[man in French] Stay.
[in Polish] I will go now.
[in French] Stay.
I don't want to hurt you. I'm hungry.
The bread.
[man chewing loudly]
Your name?
What's your name?
[ship groans, creaks]
I am Jérôme.
You?
[in Polish] Olek.
[wind rushing]
[in English]
Everyone else is inside having dinner.
And you? Are you not hungry?
Just not hungry for another conversation
about the weather,
the decline of the empire,
or the fact that
I'm a woman traveling alone.
Is it true?
That you studied medicine?
I guess Mrs. Wilson was right.
Rumors do travel fast.
Do you know there are
just as many rumors about you
as there are about me?
[delicate, mysterious music playing]
[Eyk] Right down here,
the ocean has a depth
of almost 4,000 meters.
Man has mapped out
every corner of this world.
Been to the farthest deserts,
the top of the highest mountains.
But what's down there is still a mystery.
A hidden world in the shadows.
When we get to the ship,
what do you think you'll find?
[delicate, mysterious music continues]
[inhales sharply]
I don't know.
[sailor in German] Ship ahead!
Ship ahead!
[ship's horn blares]
[unsettling synth music plays]
Captain, with all due respect,
we should get back on course.
As soon as we have radio contact,
we inform the company about the position.
We'll lower a lifeboat.
But that's insane.
We should contact the company first.
Captain, the first mate is right.
You'll be in charge of the bridge
during my absence.
This is against regulations.
You're in command of the ship.
You can't just…
The three of you, come with me.
[in English] I'm coming with you.
You might need a doctor.
[in German]
Try to reach the company again.
Let them know
that we've found the Prometheus.
What are you waiting for?
[in English] Miss Franklin.
You as well.
[furtive chattering]
[in Spanish] It's the captain.
[in German] Captain?
Shouldn't we take the priest with us?
I'm just saying. We have no idea
what awaits us over there, and--
[in Spanish] What's he saying?
I think they want you to go with them.
[priest] Where?
[Ángel] To the lost ship.
-[priest] Why would they want me?
-[Ángel] You're a priest, remember?
[in English] Your name?
-[Spanish] I don't speak their language.
-Yeah.
[in English] Your name?
-[in Spanish] Your name.
-Ramiro.
Father Ramiro.
[in English] The Prometheus
has been missing for 4 months.
I don't know
how many passengers are still alive,
what they've gone through.
But I'm sure
it would comfort them to see you.
[in Spanish] Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
[heavy clanking]
[in German] What are you doing here?
I…
He…
[sailor 1] Are you new?
I haven't seen you before.
You know crew aren't allowed out here.
Get back to your post.
Are you deaf?
Get back to your post!
[Eyk] Franz, lower the lifeboat.
[sailor 2] Why is the sea so still?
There's no wind anymore.
You know what they say.
The sea knows when death is nearby.
[sailor 3] He's right. Something is wrong.
Why aren't they responding?
Why aren't there any lights?
I'm not going there.
You.
What's your name?
[in Polish] Olek.
[in German] You two are coming with me.
[disturbing, high-pitched note playing]
[passengers murmuring anxiously]
[Krester in Danish] Can I have one?
May I have one, please?
[match rasps]
[in Spanish] What?
You don't want it anymore?
[anxious musical flourish]
[in Danish] Thanks.
[in Spanish]
I saw you before in the dining hall.
You've got an interesting face.
It's odd, but…
that scar there…
[anxious music continues]
…it almost suits you.
[Ángel exhales]
[footsteps receding rapidly]
[ominous music plays]
[Eyk in German] Hello!
Anyone there?
Hello!
Wait for us.
If we're not back in an hour, get help.
You first.
I've been part of your crew for 12 years.
He ranks lower than me.
He should stay.
[Eyk] No, you stay here.
One hour.
Then go and get help.
[low, menacing chords play]
[Maura in English] Why is nobody here?
[Eyk] Someone sent the signal.
There have to be survivors.
[ticker steadily clicking, clacking]
[ominous music builds]
[ticker stops abruptly]
[in German] It stopped.
What stopped?
The coordinates.
They stopped sending them.
They must have seen us then, surely?
Perhaps.
[ominous music swells]
[Olek in Polish] Where is everyone?
[ship creaking, groaning]
[harsh, metallic grinding]
[metal groaning ominously]
[in French] What happened here?
[eerie, asynchronous laughter]
[staticky, cacophonous music plays]
[faint laughter echoing]
[footsteps approaching]
[in English] Are you all right?
[Eyk's breath quavering]
[eerie music builds]
[eerie audio ends abruptly]
[woman in Cantonese] Nothing will change.
We stick to our plan.
I can't stand wearing this makeup
and this costume anymore.
If you had just accepted your fate,
none of this would have happened.
You're hurting me.
Well, life hurts.
You should practice your Japanese.
[in Cantonese] Would you like to dance?
[in Japanese] Would you like to dance?
Would you like to dance?
[in Cantonese] To dance?
[in Japanese] To dance?
To dance?
[in Cantonese] Nice to meet you.
[in Japanese] Nice to meet you.
[in Cantonese] We only have to pretend
for a little while longer.
Remember…
[both] Everything will be okay in the end.
[both] If it's not okay, it's not the end.
[record continuing in Cantonese]
[in Japanese] I'm much obliged.
[wind rushing]
[Eyk in English]
Someone destroyed the telegraph.
How did they send the signal?
[unsettling synth music plays]
[ominous drumbeat plays]
[low, intense synth music blasts]
[figure panting]
[wind rushing]
[intense synth music pulsing]
[Olek in Polish] Hello?
Anyone here?
[insect scuttling]
[Jérôme in French] What's she doing?
[eerie synth music playing]
[eerie synth music drones]
[jarring banging]
[in Polish] What was that?
[loud banging]
[in Portuguese]
Oh my God. Please don't do this to me.
[in Spanish] Hey, are you crazy?
You don't know what's in there!
[Ramiro breathing heavily]
[cocks gun]
[hinges creak]
[Eyk in German] Oh my God.
[in English] Are you all right?
Who put you in there?
["White Rabbit"
by Jefferson Airplane playing]
♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
♪ Go ask Alice ♪
♪ When she's ten feet tall ♪
♪ And if you go chasing rabbits ♪
♪ And you know you're going to fall ♪
♪ Tell 'em a hookah-smoking caterpillar ♪
♪ Has given you the call ♪
♪ Call Alice ♪
♪ When she was just small ♪
♪ When the men on the chessboard ♪
♪ Get up and tell you where to go ♪
♪ And you've just had
Some kind of mushroom ♪
♪ And your mind is moving low ♪
♪ Go ask Alice ♪
♪ I think she'll know ♪
♪ When logic and proportion ♪
♪ Have fallen sloppy dead ♪
♪ And the White Knight is
Talking backwards ♪
♪ And the Red Queen's off with her head ♪
♪ Remember ♪
♪ What the dormouse said ♪
♪ Feed your head ♪
[song ends]
[atmospheric, entrancing music plays]