[tender, somber music plays]
[music swells]
[music halts abruptly]
I love you.
Never forget.
I wish this moment would last forever.
It's right there.
Stored in your memory.
Weren't you the one to tell me
that one's whole reality
is actually inside one's mind?
It's all there.
You, me, this.
Inside your brain forever.
You actually listen
when I tell you things.
Listen, yes.
Agree, no.
Reality is more than neurons
firing around in your brain.
Reality is not what's on the inside.
It's what's happening on the outside.
It's this.
And this.
But none of this would exist
if it weren't for the mind
to experience it.
And, going a step further,
it actually might not exist at all.
So we'll never know whether the stimuli
in our brain are caused by
a reality or a construct of one.
[Maura chuckles]
You're a hopeless romantic.
Constructed reality or not, I'm starving.
Maura.
Never forget.
Never ever.
[door closes]
[sighs]
[deep vibrations rumbling]
[siren wails]
[woman over PA] Initiating shutdown.
Maura?
[staticky glitching crackles]
[siren continues wailing]
Maura?
[glitchy audio squawks]
-[Maura] Wake up.
-[gasping]
[footsteps in distance]
[bangs on door] Maura, is that you?
[banging rapidly]
Maura, let me out of here!
The shutdown has started.
We don't have much time
before everyone will die again.
Where is my device?
[banging rapidly]
Maura!
I beg you!
Please!
I need my device. Please!
[banging on door] Maura!
-[Maura's footsteps receding]
-[sighs]
-[brooding cover of "White Rabbit" plays]
-♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ When logic and proportion ♪
♪ Have fallen sloppy dead ♪
♪ And the White Knight is
Talking backwards ♪
♪ And the Red Queen's off with her head ♪
[singer vocalizing]
[song trails off]
[waves crashing]
[unsettling vocalizations]
[Tove in Danish] We're going to capsize.
No one survives a storm like this.
We need to find the captain!
None of us knows how to steer this ship!
This is God's revenge.
[in Portuguese]
If God exists and if He created this,
I swear He must be crazy.
[in French] We need to warn the others
in the engine room.
[in Portuguese] Room. The engine room?
Yes, the crew is still there.
That brute, he will know what to do.
[in Danish] What are you saying?
Are we going to look
for the captain or what?
[in French] This is ridiculous!
Can someone tell us what we should do now?
[in English] We need to find the captain.
And Miss Franklin.
[in French] Are you unwell?
Just a little seasick.
That's all.
[all grunt, flinch]
Let's hurry! We need to find someone
to pilot this steamship!
[in Danish] Are we done talking or what?
Hurry!
[door opens]
[wind whistling]
[in French] Aren't you coming?
[in English] Just find Miss Franklin.
[raggedly] I'll be fine.
[eerie, resounding music plays]
What if…
[panel creaks]
[rod clangs]
[suspenseful music plays]
[thunder booms]
Hey!
I'm looking for the captain.
Have you seen him?
I thought he was with you.
Where is the captain?
-I thought he was back on the ship.
-Back on the ship?
Was he gone?
I meant,
I thought he'd returned to the bridge.
The boy, did you find him?
[Mrs. Wilson] Miss Franklin.
Are you all right?
Where is everyone?
They're looking for the captain.
-He's not here?
-No.
-What is this?
-I wouldn't touch it if I were you.
Actually, I was hoping
you could tell me what it is.
I have never seen anything like it.
I think I'm gonna die.
-We're all gonna die!
-You're not.
No one is going to die.
Just think of it all as a bad dream.
What? What are you talking about?
Maybe he's back in his memory.
Please, wait. Wait.
No, Miss Franklin.
No, please, please, don't leave me!
[tense music continues]
[device powering up]
[in German] Where are you, you little rat?
[tense music fades away]
[staticky glitching]
[in English] Eyk?
[woman in German] May I help you?
[in English]
I'm looking for Eyk. Eyk Larsen.
[in German] Are you lost?
[in English] I don't understand.
[in German] Are you well?
May I help you?
Are you lost?
Are you well?
[erratically] May I help you?
Are you lost?
Are you well?
[glitching, skipping]
May I help you? Are you lost?
Are you well?
[tense notes chime]
[tense music continues]
[thunder rumbling]
[staticky buzzing]
[in Portuguese] Now. We're going to sink.
Of course He wants to punish us.
Your God,
He is not forgiving.
He is crazy and cruel.
[in Danish]
This won't do you any good, Father.
In this water, you won't drown.
You'll freeze to death.
You understand? Freeze!
We need to continue.
Keep going.
[grunting with effort]
[Iben] Tove?
What do you want with these people?
He's not a priest.
And she's clearly a whore.
This is God's choice.
-And I'm staying here.
-[Tove] Stop it.
Stop.
God will not protect us.
We have not been chosen to follow him.
We both know damn well
that I'm not carrying God's child.
And you're not hearing God's voice.
You are crazy.
Tove. Tove.
Are you coming?
[Anker breathes shakily]
[mournful, unsettling music plays]
Go.
No.
No. No!
It'll be all right.
[whimpering] No.
[Tove sobs]
Go.
[shuddering gasp]
[mournful music continues]
Let us pray, Anker. Come.
Yes.
Let us pray.
[wind rushing]
[tense percussive music plays]
[glitchy crackle]
[echoing thud]
[metal groans]
[in French] Lucien?
What's going on? What's going on?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Clémence?
Thank God, you're okay.
[Tove in Danish] Hey. Storm outside.
Waves high like mountains.
It's coming from all sides.
It's everywhere.
Nobody is on the bridge.
The first mate left,
and the captain hasn't returned.
[Franz in German]
Olek, you have to take the helm.
We have to navigate
straight into the storm. Head on.
If the hull stays
parallel to the waves, we will capsize.
Hey! We have to keep the engines running,
or we don't stand a chance.
Hey. Where are you going?
We have to close the bulkheads,
or water will come in everywhere.
I'll help.
[Olek in Polish] Ling Yi.
I must go to the bridge.
[in Cantonese] I'll go wherever you go.
[distant rattling, creaking]
[suspenseful music playing]
[grunts]
[frame scraping]
[disconcerting ululations]
[ululations trail off]
[door closes]
[glitchy audio burst]
[shrill pulsing]
[poignant music playing]
[portal clanks]
[in English] Where have you been?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I tried to get here as fast as I could.
It's happening again.
They're shutting it down.
But you were right.
We've never got this far before.
It's not lost.
Have you found the code?
Mum?
She still doesn't remember.
But we will get her out
so she can end this loop once and for all.
You have to find the code.
She has to remember where it is.
I just need to find my device
so I can stop this.
Dad?
[mysterious music playing]
She will wake up this time.
I'm sure she will.
[wind whistling]
[in German] Gotcha.
[device beeping]
[beeping]
[electronic trilling]
[in Polish] We have to stop the rudder.
Tighter!
[service cart crashes]
No.
[plaintive vocalizations]
[vocalizations continue]
[door opens]
[door closes]
I'm sorry you had to find out this way.
His name is Elliot.
He's our son.
That's impossible.
I can't have children.
Doctors said I could never have children.
It's a false memory.
I would remember having a child.
So, why don't I remember?
Because you wanted to forget.
[Maura] I would feel it if I had a son.
Why don't I feel anything?
Because you wanted to get rid of the pain.
Why?
[low, mournful music plays]
I know you remember.
Somewhere in there,
[glitchy burst reverberates]
[delicate, yearnful music plays]
[glitching intensifies]
This isn't real. You're not real.
You're trapped here. You all are.
Trapped in what?
You said it yourself.
We will never know whether the stimuli
in our brains are caused by reality
or just by a construct of one.
A construct of one?
This isn't real.
[ominous synth music plays]
This is a simulation.
Plato's cave allegory.
You're watching shadows on the wall,
and you think that they're the reality.
But if you could only look
over your shoulder,
you would see
what's causing those shadows.
What's actually real.
You forgot.
You forgot what's real.
But you have to remember.
You have to wake up.
Or there will be nothing left
to wake up for,
and your consciousness
will be trapped in here forever.
[siren wails]
We're running out of time.
I need to get you out of here
before it restarts.
[storm raging]
[straining]
[sobbing]
[countdown clock pulsing]
[door opens]
[tense music playing]
Sir.
He knows where the boy is hiding.
Here.
They're shutting down the simulation.
There's a code, an override.
It's the only way out
before everything restarts.
It's somewhere on the ship.
You have to remember where it is.
I don't understand. Why would I know?
Try to remember.
You hid it, but you made yourself forget.
In here, a code can be any object.
A switch, a door, a key. Anything.
[eerie, unsettling music plays]
I don't know what it opens.
You've had it here the whole time?
It's not mine. I got it with the envelope.
Someone sent it to me.
I think it was my brother.
You will wake up this time. I promise.
[in French] Clémence.
[breathing erratically]
Lucien! Lucien!
No! Your medicine!
Lucien, your vial, where is it? Lucien!
Where are his vials?
In a box! In our cabin! Come on!
Help me. Let's carry him.
[in Spanish] Well,
I suppose it's up to us now.
[ship creaks ominously]
[protrusions rustling]
[in English] What is that?
Just as in any program,
there are hidden cheats
and shortcuts inside the simulation.
Trust me, you'll understand it all
once you wake up.
My shell, the… the device,
do you still have it?
What are you doing?
Once they flush us out,
everything will start again.
This run will go into the archive,
just like the others.
But this time it will be different.
I'll anchor us to it
so we'll go through the same port.
This will buy us more time.
-This has happened before?
-Dozens of times.
Every simulation runs eight days.
None of the ships ever made it
to their destination.
You're caught in a loop,
simulation after simulation.
We have to get to Elliot.
[mysterious chiming]
[Ling Yi's mother in Cantonese]
Ling Yi! Come.
Come with me.
[Ling Yi breathing tremulously]
Mom!
[in Polish] What are you doing?
Fucking hell.
[in Cantonese] Mom!
[wind whistling]
[in Polish] What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
[Ling Yi whimpering]
[Olek] Quick!
We have to get back!
[screams]
[Olek] Ling Yi!
[Ling Yi panting]
You won't die. Not today.
I promise.
Come.
[wave surging]
[in Cantonese] Olek!
[Olek screams]
No!
Olek!
[grunting]
[Jérôme in French] Hey!
[disconcerting music plays]
[Ramiro coughing]
[in Spanish] Ángel!
[tender, mournful music plays]
Ángel!
No! No! No! This isn't happening. No!
Someone. Help me, please! Someone!
Wait.
Ángel. Ángel. Ángel.
My love.
[weakly] I never understood
why you fell in love with someone like me.
You are the gentlest,
most loyal man I've ever met.
And you were right.
You're better off without me.
[Ramiro] No.
No. Don't leave me. No, my love.
I'm scared.
[Ramiro] No. No. No.
[weeping quietly]
[no audible dialogue]
[Franz grunts]
[both straining]
[tender, mournful music continues]
[in Danish] Iben, my love.
We can't stay here. Come.
Don't worry about me.
If this is what He wants for me,
who am I to deny His wish?
You think He wants you to die?
God wants you to die?
It's what you want! It's what you want!
Iben, wake up.
I know His true path for us.
For all of us.
[Franz in German] It won't close!
Come! We have to close the next one along.
There's no handle.
Why isn't there a handle?
-[in Danish] What do we do?
-[Franz in German] Dammit.
No.
Promise you'll stay alive.
[Tove in Danish] What are you doing?
[in German] No!
No!
No! Open up!
[Anker in Danish] It will be all right.
I am not going to leave you.
I'll never leave you.
[Anker exclaims, pants]
[in German] Stop! No!
[door opens]
[crew member in English]
Sir, I found him and the pyramid.
[Henry] Every time,
they make the same mistakes.
And every time, they die.
Because they can't
get rid of their emotions.
But that's what makes them weak.
It's human nature's ultimate flaw.
One shouldn't base a choice on love,
anger, hate.
They're just silly feelings
that cloud the mind.
[ship creaking ominously]
No.
No!
[Daniel grunting in frustration]
-Where is it?
-I don't know!
I don't know.
-[PA system squawks]
-[tapping on microphone]
[Henry] You've come far this time.
Using the Prometheus
to regain access was a smart move.
Nevertheless, you've failed.
Again.
Your little reprogramming won't help.
Everyone on this ship will eventually die
and take part in the next simulation.
You're all trapped in this loop.
Maura, you have something that I want.
Why are you doing this?
What do you want from me?
-Why am I--
-[toggles mic]
I want the key.
And, in return, you will keep your son.
What have you done? Where is Elliot?
What have you done to him?
The key.
You know where to find me.
[PA system crackles, powers off]
I'll fix this.
You have to trust me.
[mournful music plays]
I love you.
Never forget.
[plaintive vocalizations]
[pyramid clicking, clacking]
[Henry] The Kerberos
will be moved into the archive.
Your mother will bring me the key,
and this will finally come to an end.
[computer] Shutdown in ten,
nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four,
three, two, one, zero.
[plaintive vocalizations continue]
[music fades away]
[distant, low rumbling]
[wind rushing]
["The Wind" by Cat Stevens plays]
♪ I listen to the wind
To the wind of my soul ♪
♪ Where I’ll end up
Well, I think only God really knows ♪
♪ I’ve sat upon the settin' sun ♪
♪ But never, never, never, never ♪
♪ I never wanted water once ♪
♪ No, never, never, never ♪
[song trails off]
[entrancing outro music plays]