[distorted, unsettling audio]
[unsettling audio crescendos]
[low, sinister music plays]
[muffled straining]
[muffled screaming]
[glitchy audio squawks]
-[Maura] Wake up.
-[gasps]
[breathing shakily]
[panting]
[passengers chattering indistinctly]
[man laughs]
[passengers continue chattering]
[audio warbles disconcertingly]
Ah, there you are.
Sit down.
Your mother and I were discussing
the unfortunate circumstance
of the ship being turned around.
And I was just telling her
sometimes one has to adjust
to a situation as it unfolds.
With every calamity comes…
[low, menacing music plays]
…opportunity.
Meet me in my room after breakfast.
[in Cantonese] Don't keep me waiting.
[mother] Look what you've done.
We should have never gotten on this ship.
It was a mistake.
All of it… a huge mistake.
-[brooding cover of "White Rabbit" plays]
-♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
[singer vocalizing]
♪ When logic and proportion ♪
♪ Have fallen sloppy dead ♪
♪ And the White Knight is
Talking backwards ♪
♪ And the Red Queen's off with her head ♪
[singer vocalizing]
[song trails off]
[ship's horn blares]
[chain rattling]
[in Danish] Ada?
Ada?
[man in English]
There's no sign of bruising.
The skin is unbroken.
Bones intact.
[sniffs]
No discoloration in the throat.
Rules out poisoning.
Looks like natural causes to me.
Possible stroke or heart attack.
I've met her.
Two days ago, in third class.
She looked healthy.
There was nothing wrong with her.
That's why I think it's a mistake
for women to venture into medicine.
They're too attached to their emotions
to clearly perceive the facts at hand.
Ever heard of Darwin?
Survival of the fittest?
It's the process of natural selection
and a way for God
to clean out the bad seeds.
Now, if I can finish my breakfast.
Thank you.
[footsteps receding]
[Eyk] You met her?
Hmm.
There's a pregnant girl downstairs.
This is her sister.
[in German] Don't tell anyone.
But, Captain,
shouldn't we let the family know?
[ship creaking, rumbling]
Someone must have given
the order to reduce speed.
[bell ringing]
We had a clear view.
And then from one second to the next,
this.
First the compasses, and now the fog.
We can't navigate anymore.
What should we do?
We hold our position.
Wait until the fog has cleared.
[in English] I need to show you something.
[tense percussive music plays]
[Franz in German] This is a mistake.
Just like every other decision
he's made on this trip.
We've gone off course.
He turned the ship back around.
He's completely lost his mind.
[tense percussive music
intensifies, halts]
[Eyk in English] This ribbon.
It belonged to my daughter.
I found it on the Prometheus.
She's dead.
So are her sisters.
And my wife.
They died in a fire almost two years ago.
Or at least that's what I thought.
But yesterday, I saw Nina.
How is that possible?
[discomforting music plays]
Can we see things that aren't there
and still believe they're real?
Our brain isn't always entirely reliable.
Everything that we see and feel and hear
are the result of electrical impulses.
And sometimes
we misinterpret those impulses.
It's what makes people go mad.
I'm sorry for your losses.
[inhales shakily]
[breathes shakily]
[Eyk grunts]
Am I mad?
Or do you see what I see?
I know this ship inside out.
This is not supposed to be here.
I have no idea what's going on here
and why my daughter's ribbon
was on the Prometheus.
But the ship company,
I believe they're trying
to hide something.
Whatever happened on the Prometheus,
the captain must have written it down.
I'm going back to find the logbook.
I'm coming with you.
[tense audio distortions swell, fade away]
[woman in Norwegian]
Why has the ship stopped?
No one tells us anything.
None of us want to go back.
When they turned the ship around,
they stole our future,
and now they don't even care
if one of us goes missing.
Iben, I'm sure we'll find her.
[indistinct chatter]
[in Danish] You didn't find her?
Do something.
It's through prayer
that we find the right path.
Pray with us.
[Tove] Father! We have to find Ada.
Anker, lead us in prayer.
[passengers murmur]
[Mrs. Wilson in English] Keep going.
Undress.
[in Cantonese]
Don't pretend you don't understand.
Undress.
[in English]
You're prettier than I thought.
Lie down.
I need to see if you're clean.
I'm sure you're
just as frustrated as everyone else
with the ship being turned around.
But if my experience
has taught me one thing,
it's that frustration and boredom
are great motivators
to seek out other pleasures.
Human behavior is predictable.
Desire meets opportunity.
Et voilà.
This might hurt a little.
[stifled whimper]
[Mrs. Wilson] Interesting.
Are you still a virgin?
[unsettling music plays]
Considering you're meant to be
one of my best girls,
I find that very surprising.
Stop.
[ragged gasp]
I don't like to be deceived.
But I do like to be surprised.
You truly are a rare bird, aren't you?
And rarity has value.
All the more now.
I hope you knew what this job was
when you took the other girl's place.
Be ready at 8:00.
[Franz in German] With all due respect,
you can't leave the ship again.
People want to know what is going on.
Dammit.
I want to know what is going on.
That boy, why won't he speak?
[sailor] He's right.
There is something wrong with that ship.
We should leave the Prometheus behind
and set the Kerberos back on course.
[Eyk] Lower the boat.
[sighs]
[Eyk] Franz.
[winch grinding]
[rowboat splashes]
[Franz] He's a drunken wreck.
And you know it.
We must act.
[door opens, closes heavily]
[intense, mysterious synth music plays]
[device clicks]
[device beeping, whirring]
[electricity surging, thrumming]
[intense synth music swells, fades away]
[tense synth music plays]
[mysterious clattering]
[in English] This morning
in the infirmary,
why did you want me there?
I wanted a second opinion.
And contrary to what Dr. Murray said,
I believe you don't let emotions
cloud your judgment.
Thank you.
It was…
kind of you to take the boy in.
He lost everything.
Do you have children?
A couple of years ago,
I had a miscarriage.
There were complications,
and I can't have children anymore.
I'm sorry.
Why are you so afraid to go back home?
Because I lost everything.
[woman in Cantonese] She knows we lied.
She knows that we are not
who we say we are.
Are you happy now?
Is this how you imagined it?
Your freedom?
I tried to protect you.
-I wanted a better life for you.
-A better life?
All you have ever done is put me in a box.
Every time those men
came on board, I had to hide.
You put me in a prison.
You can call it whatever you want.
But at least
you didn't have to sell yourself.
Is that such a big deal?
I've seen you do that often enough.
I know how it is done.
There is no turning back after this.
It's the kind of dirt that never rubs off.
You'll become what I have become, a whore.
Ling Yi!
[intense, brooding music plays]
[mother] Ling Yi!
[panting]
[door opens]
Ling Yi, come back!
Ling Yi!
Please, where are you?
[glitchy audio squawks]
[eerie chiming]
Ling Yi.
You killed her.
[younger Ling Yi] I didn't mean to.
[mother] How much
did you put in her drink?
I just wanted to make her sleep.
It's too late now.
[tense panting]
Come give me a hand.
We have to get rid of her.
[footsteps]
Ling Yi.
Hurry!
Stop! Stop it!
I'm in here.
Please stop!
[audio warbles disconcertingly]
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out!
Help! Help!
Help!
[muffled screaming]
[Ling Yi panting]
[Olek in Polish] What happened?
It's okay now.
Easy.
Are you cold?
[Ling Yi shivering]
It's dirty, but it's warm.
I'm Olek.
Olek.
[in Cantonese] Ling Yi.
[mother] Ling Yi, I beg you!
Where are you?
Ling Yi!
[in Polish] I know a better hiding place.
Come.
[man in Norwegian] Ada is still missing,
and why are we not moving?
Maybe they are thinking
about turning back to America.
Well, we paid for this.
They better bring us to our destination.
We can't go back home. What do they think?
That we have money left
to pay for a second fare?
[woman] It's all because of
that other ship out there.
It's cursed.
And that boy they found
brought the curse with him.
Or why else would he,
of all passengers, still be alive?
You, are you part of the crew?
What is happening?
Answer me.
[in German] Do you speak German?
A little.
We found your sister.
[shallow gasp]
[passengers murmur in agitation]
[door clanking]
[in Danish] Who did this?
Who did this?
[in German] A doctor examined her.
He couldn't tell exactly what happened.
[Tove sniffs]
[mournful dirge plays]
[ominous synth chord pulses]
[mournful dirge continues]
[in Danish] Get out of my way.
Get out of my way!
[in Spanish]
Look what the tide brought in.
You must stop acting like this,
or I'll start to think you don't like me.
[ship creaking, groaning]
[in Danish] I'm looking for my sister.
[in Spanish] I have no idea
what you're saying.
[in Danish] We don't know where she is.
[in Spanish] That scar on your face,
how did you get it?
We all wear masks.
We all pretend.
Presenting a perfect illusion
on the outside,
while we desperately try to hide
who we are on the inside.
I was forced to hide
who I am my whole life.
I didn't choose my mask.
My mother chose it for me.
But you…
[gate clangs]
…you can't hide.
[gate rattles]
Everyone sees you for what you are.
[rattling]
Don't tell me you don't like it.
-[Ángel sighs]
-[fabric stretching]
[gate clangs]
[chuckles]
[sultry synth music plays]
[Ángel gasps breathily]
[gate pounds rhythmically]
[Ángel whimpers]
[Ángel moans]
[rattling increases in tempo]
[music swells, fades away]
[wind whistling]
[Maura in English] It almost looks as if
the fog was there to stop us from moving.
[Eyk] The logbook.
It should be here.
There's one here as well.
[Maura] Give me a hand.
[mysterious music playing]
[Eyk] Do you see anything?
[tense percussive music plays]
[high-pitched, mysterious tones play]
[low, foreboding music plays]
[two knocks at door]
[door unlocks]
[foreboding music continues]
[door closes]
Did you find it?
[Eyk] Why would they build
a tiled shaft there?
It doesn't make sense.
A few months ago…
the fleet, a total of three German ships,
was sold to a British investor.
Henry Singleton.
The ships went to the dry dock
for three months.
They put in the new communication system,
and they refurbished everything.
This sign, the triangle,
it's the ship company's symbol.
They clearly put this here.
There's something else they changed.
Follow me.
[uneasy synth music playing]
[Olek in Polish]
I know it's not first class, but…
Uh, if you're hungry,
I can get something to eat.
It's not a problem.
I can go and get something.
Wait here. I'll be back in a moment.
[door opens]
[wind rushing eerily]
[foreboding music builds]
[glitchy audio squawks]
[anxious panting]
[in Cantonese] Mei Mei?
Are you all right?
Are you human or a ghost?
You must leave now.
My ship isn't leaving until later tonight.
I said goodbye
to the girls at the brothel.
Oh, and I wanted to show you something.
Look how pretty it is.
They told me I'll get more later.
[chuckles]
And while I'm waiting
in England for the ship to America,
they will give me dance lessons
and teach me Japanese.
[eerie, unsettling string music plays]
Aren't you happy for me? I finally have
a chance to get out of here.
Why is this happening?
Why is this happening again?
What are you talking about?
Mei Mei?
[Mei Mei grunts]
[labored breathing, pained grunts]
[Ling Yi] Did you drink that?
You offered it to me a minute ago.
No.
This can't be happening again.
It was an accident.
I've seen my mother give it
to the men that come here.
They've always woken up again.
I just wanted you to sleep.
So when you woke up,
I would have taken your place
and been on my way to England.
[Ling Yi breathing raggedly]
Wake up this time!
[glitchy audio squawks]
-[door opening]
-[Ling Yi sobbing]
[in Polish] What happened?
Come on.
Calm down.
[in Cantonese] I've done
something horrible.
This kimono
doesn't belong to me.
This is not me.
It's all a lie.
We are not supposed to have dreams.
[passengers chattering]
[chatter subsides]
[in Danish] Where have you been?
Krester.
Krester, stop! Stop!
Stop. Stop.
We have to open the window…
[plaintive music plays]
…or her soul can't leave.
Stop.
[Krester sobs]
[plaintive music intensifies]
[tense percussive line plays]
[jarring stinger]
[agitated, dissonant music plays]
[bell clanging]
[music intensifies]
[music trails off]
[Eyk in English]
They put this here as well.
It's supposed to measure
the steam pressure
and send signals up to the bridge.
But on the Kerberos, it never worked.
You think they lied?
They put it here for something else?
Whatever they've done to the ship,
it doesn't explain where everyone went.
How hot do these get?
[Eyk] Up to 900 degrees Celsius.
A cremator generates
that kind of temperature.
[high-pitched, mysterious tone plays]
You think they burned the bodies?
You have to look out for tiny fractures
of bones and teeth.
[Maura scraping through residue]
[high-pitched, mysterious tone plays]
[uneasy, dissonant music plays]
[high-pitched, mysterious tones playing]
[uneasy music continues]
Have you found something?
No.
We should return now.
[high-pitched, mysterious tones playing]
[footsteps approaching]
-[shudders]
-[door opens]
[door closes, locks]
[in Cantonese] I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
You were right.
We're not supposed to have dreams.
And if we take what doesn't belong to us…
our dreams turn into nightmares.
[low, sinister music plays]
Tell Mrs. Wilson that I'm ready.
[sinister music swells]
[music trails off]
[unsettling atonal music playing]
[door opens]
[vials clink]
[drawer clattering]
[footsteps approaching]
[in French] Are you going out?
Yeah.
I'm going to get some air.
Want me to come with you?
No.
[elegant koto music playing]
[door creaks shut]
[koto music intensifies]
[knocking at door]
[koto music continues]
[complex koto music continues]
[music halts]
[in French] Stop.
Don't. That's not what I want.
I'd just like to stay here for a while.
If you don't mind.
Things never work out
the way you imagine they will.
This is exactly
what I wanted my whole life.
First class.
Fine clothes.
I thought I deserved a different life.
None of that matters anymore.
Don't be afraid.
It never lasts long.
[Lucien chokes, grunts]
[loud thud]
[Lucien coughs]
[Lucien shivers]
[in English] Are you all right?
You haven't said a word
since we left the Prometheus.
Better not tell anyone where we were.
[Franz in German]
These aren't the only ones.
We found three more bodies
in the crew quarters.
Just the same as the little girl.
No blood.
No bruises.
Nothing.
You're the first mate.
You must take command of the ship.
You said it yourself.
There's something wrong with that ship.
Something killed everyone over there,
and now the same thing is happening here.
Why did the company want us
to sink the ship?
Maybe they didn't want
whatever is on that ship to get off.
You heard the captain.
We wait.
[Franz exhales]
[tense percussive music plays]
[passengers chattering]
[chatter grows agitated and tense]
I know what you're thinking.
I know you feel mistreated.
Treated unfairly.
[murmurs of assent]
You're not the only ones.
People are dying like flies on our ship.
And what does the captain do?
Nothing.
I say we fight.
[passenger] Yes!
[Franz] And set the Kerberos
back on course.
[rallying cries]
Who's with me?
[all shout]
Good. Hand out the guns.
Hey! You, Olek!
[chatter subsides]
[tense, arpeggiated music]
[Franz] Stop him
before he warns the captain!
[all clamoring]
[metal door clanging]
[in Polish] This is a fucking mutiny!
This is insane!
[door slams shut, locks]
[in French] Looks like this trip hasn't
turned out the way you planned either.
[mutineers chatter]
[man in Norwegian] This way.
[agitated chatter in distance]
-[footsteps approach]
-[door opens]
[in Spanish] Ramiro.
You won't believe what is happening.
People are arming themselves.
Where were you?
Did you hear what I said?
There's gonna be a mutiny.
They're overthrowing the captain.
We're going to America.
[Ramiro] Were you with him?
Jesus, Ramiro.
You sound like a jealous housewife.
Did you hear what I said?
We get what we want.
They're turning the ship around.
Maybe I don't want that anymore.
Are you on your period?
Do you ever take anything seriously?
You constantly make me feel
like I'm less than you.
That all of this is somehow my fault.
But it isn't.
It's you.
You made me do all of this.
None of this would have ever happened.
You and I would have never happened.
Ángel, for Christ's sake.
I killed a man.
I fucking took someone's life.
And now I'm wearing his clothes.
And all because of you.
Because you can't control yourself!
How can you be like this?
[moody synth music playing]
You promised you'd change.
You cannot change the nature of things.
I am who I am.
And you are who you are.
Nothing will change that.
Where are you going?
To do the right thing.
To warn the captain.
[door closes]
[tense instrumental music plays]
[sighs]
[music trails off]
[low, unsettling chord plays]
[Daniel in English]
Odd, this fog, isn't it?
Almost as if someone
had sent it here on purpose,
to stop that madman
dragging us all back to Europe.
I don't think he's mad.
You agree with him
turning the ship around?
I just think I understand
what he's been through.
He lost everything he loves.
He's a deeply hurt man whose judgment
has been clouded by his past experiences.
I lost someone too.
[multiple, heavy footsteps approaching]
[Daniel] Lock yourself in the cabin.
I told you, people aren't going
to sit still and just let it happen.
[pounding on door]
Father Ramiro?
[in Portuguese] They want
to turn the ship back around, to America.
They've got guns.
[in English] I don't understand
what you're saying.
["The Killing Moon"
by Echo & the Bunnymen plays]
[lock clicks]
[in Danish] We're turning the ship around.
[mutineers yell]
[high-pitched, shrill tone]
♪ Under blue moon, I saw you ♪
♪ So soon you'll take me ♪
♪ Up in your arms, too late to beg you ♪
[console hums, beeps]
♪ Or cancel it, though I know it must be ♪
♪ The killing time ♪
[electricity sparks]
♪ Unwillingly mine ♪
♪ Fate ♪
♪ Up against your will ♪
♪ Through the thick and thin ♪
[console whirs]
♪ He will wait until ♪
♪ You give yourself to him ♪
♪ In starlit nights, I saw you ♪
♪ So cruelly, you kissed me ♪
♪ Your lips, a magic world ♪
♪ Your sky, all hung with jewels ♪
♪ The killing moon ♪
♪ Will come too soon ♪
♪ Fate ♪
♪ Up against your will ♪
♪ Through the thick and thin ♪
♪ He will wait until ♪
♪ You give yourself to him ♪
[moody, mysterious outro music plays]